((リン：カカシ…))
（カカシ）落ちない。
Kakashi...
It won't wash off!
for some reason the moon is one size larger tonight
konya no tsuki wa nazeka hitomawari ookikute
it's shining brighter than it usually does
itsumo yori akaruku terasu
I trudge along the road home with my shoulders hunched
senaka wo marumete tobotobo kaeru michi
at any time I will always have a friend
donna toki mo mikata wa iru
without saying a word, it's all right to cry
nani mo iwazu naketara ii ne
once my tears dry, it will all be over
namida ga karetara owari
I need to become stronger...
motto boku ga tsuyoku naranakya
sorrow is the first step towards independence
kanashimi wa jiritsu he no ippo
how many times do I have to get hurt to forget the pain?
nando kizutsukeba itami wo wasureru
when I bleed red, I'm reminded of life
akai chi wo nagaseba inochi wo omoidasu sa
I collapse on the road with my arms and legs spread out
michi ni taore dainoji ni
I look up at the sky and think
sora wo miagete omou
true loneliness is someone without a past
shin no kodoku to wa kako no nai mono
someone who only knows the present
ima shika shiranu mono
Kakashi: Shadow of the Anbu
A Mask that Hides the Heart
Accept this from the Hokage!
（シカク）火影様よりの書状
受け取るがいい。
Deliver it to Lord Tsuchikage
土影様に届けよ
至急　ご返答願いたいとな。
and relay to him that we desire
an immediate response!
There's no need to deliver
anything to him.
届けるまでもない
ここで返答してやる。
We'll give you your answer
right here!
Sometimes it's best not
to be so hasty.
慌てぬほうがよいときもある。
What?!
なに！？
The Fourth Kazekage?
四代目風影！
Why is the Hidden Sand here?
なぜ　砂隠れが。
This is Hidden Sand territory.
ここは　我ら砂隠れの
国境でもある。
It would be unwise to have
an incident occur here.
ここで騒ぎを起こされては困る。
We'll put out any sparks
that rain down over us.
降りかかる火の粉は
振り払わねばなるまい。
The Sand will move accordingly,
as the Sand.
砂は砂として動く。
Remember that,
whatever you decide to do.
それを承知で
行動してもらいたい。
Scatter!
散！
What about the request to enter into
the peace treaty?
平和条約締結の申し込み
どうなさるおつもりです？
Naturally, it will be turned down.
当然　お断りなさるんでしょうな。
Whatever the Hidden Leaf negotiates
with the Hidden Sand,
いかに木ノ葉隠れが
砂隠れと組もうが→
nothing will challenge
the unity of the Stone.
我らの　一枚岩の結束に
敵うものはありません。
– Right!
– Exactly!
そのとおりです。
Silence!
（オオノキ）静まれぃ！
Naturally, I am proud of
the unity of the Stone.
もちろん　岩隠れの結束は
わしの誇りじゃぜ。
しかし　岩隠れの命運をかけ→
However...
With the pride on our line,
we sent 1000 of our shinobi.
一千余名の忍を投入した
侵攻作戦を→
And I hear that it took just one of them,
the Yellow Flash, to stop the invasion.
頓挫させたのは→
黄色い閃光
ただ１人だったと聞く。
And that's the reality of it.
それもまた事実じゃぜ。
I hear they're going to enter
into a peace treaty
（ライドウ）今度　岩隠れと平和条約が
締結されるんだってさ。
with the Hidden Stone.
How much faith can we put
in a single piece of paper?
（ゲンマ）紙切れ一枚に
どんだけ効力があるか。
（ガイ）うむ…　それは言える。
That's for sure.
You guys, think about
the burden on Lord Third!
お前たちも
三代目様の苦労も考えろって。
In any case, the long, great war
will be over for now.
（アスマ）とにかく長かった大戦も
ひとまず　これで終わりだ。
Let's toast with some dumplings!
（紅）おだんごで乾杯しましょう。
Hey, Kakashi!
（ガイ）お～い　カカシ！
Want to join us for some dumplings?
こっち来て　だんご食わないか？
He's not too sociable these days.
最近　つきあい悪いな　アイツ。
悩みでもあるのか？
Is something bothering him?
Well, you can't expect him
to be jumping for joy.
そりゃ　手放しで　はしゃげる
心境じゃないだろ。
やっぱり　オビトとリンのことが…。
Are you talking about
Obito and Rin?
Yeah.
あぁ　心に大きな傷が残るさ。
That would definitely leave
a hole in your heart...
((カカシ…))
Kakashi...
リン…。
Rin...
HOW A SHINOBI SHOULD DIE
（ホムラ）ご苦労じゃった。
Well done!
We can breathe
a sigh of relief for a while.
（コハル）ひとまず胸を
なでおろしたわい。
Are you satisfied with
an agreement like this?
（ダンゾウ）こんな条約で満足ですか？
To forgive
the Hidden Stone's actions
岩隠れの活動を認め→
and drop our demands
for compensation...
賠償請求権を放棄するとは…。
It's as though we lost the war!
戦争に負けたも同然の内容。
ヒルゼンは　どう思うか？
What do you think, Hiruzen?
Continuing the war
any further would be disastrous
（ヒルゼン）これ以上の戦争の継続は→
疲弊しきった木ノ葉にとっても
致命的。
for the already
exhausted Hidden Leaf.
It's a step toward finding
common ground...
同意を導き出すための譲歩…。
このたびの大戦で→
Many of my friends gave
their lives for this great war!
多くの盟友たちが
犠牲になっておる！
It's like they died in vain!
彼らを犬死にさせたも同然だ。
And I assume full responsibility
for that.
その責任は
すべて火影である　わしにある。
How will you take responsibility?
どう責任をとるつもりだ？
三代目火影の座を辞し→
I intend to step down as the Third Hokage,
and have the Fourth Hokage installed.
四代目に譲るつもりじゃ。
残念だのう。
How regrettable...
The Third Hokage was
doing a fine job...
三代目は　よくやっておったが。
Hmm...
元を正せば
三代目が甘い考えゆえ→
Truth be told, the Third Hokage
was too soft...
and he allowed the village
to be pushed into a corner.
あそこまで
里が追い込まれたのだ。
今　必要とされる火影とは
里に変革を成し→
We need a Hokage
who will change things,
and enforce the laws of the shinobi.
忍に掟を徹底させる。
そんな人材だ。
We need someone like that.
And? Is there such a person?
ほう　適当な者はおるのかえ？
I recommend Orochimaru,
one of the Legendary Sannin.
わしは　伝説の三忍と謳われる→
大蛇丸を推薦する。
– Oh...
– Him?
三代目は　どう思うのだ？
What do you think, Lord Third?
大蛇丸は
戦乱の時代にあってこそ→
Orochimaru is truly a genius
in this age of war.
才能に満ち溢れる天才
と言えましょう。
しかし　その瞳の奥には→
However...
A sinister will and greed lurk
deep behind those eyes.
悪意と野望が潜んでおります。
そのような素養を持つ者に→
Such a person cannot be given
the duties of a Hokage.
火影は任せられませぬ。
Lord Third!
三代目！
波風ミナトを推薦いたします。
I recommend Minato Namikaze.
A pupil of Jiraiya...
自来也の弟子筋にあたる男。
In other words,
a disciple of your disciple.
つまり　三代目の孫弟子じゃ。
A man so skilled,
he's nicknamed the Yellow Flash.
黄色い閃光と異名をとる手練。
Oh!
ほう。
Minato is still too young.
ミナトは　まだ若い！
神無毘橋に勝利し→
He emerged victorious
at the Battle of Kannabi Bridge,
第三次忍界大戦
終結に導いた功績は大。
and distinguished himself
by leading the way to end
of the Third Great Shinobi War.
I am opposed!
わしは反対だ。
What about the rest of you?
他の皆は　どうじゃえ？
お前は　火の意志を
継ぐ者と思っておる。
I believe that you will carry on
the Will of Fire.
So I want to entrust you with
the future of the Hidden Leaf...
そんなお前に　これからの木ノ葉を
そして　忍世界の未来を託す。
and the shinobi world.
受けてくれるな？
You will accept, won't you?
（ミナト）三代目の信頼に
お応えできるように。
I shall do my best to deserve
your trust, Lord Third.
I wish I could have passed this on
under better circumstances...
本来なら　もっと
よい環境を整えたうえで→
引き継げたらと
思っていたのだが→
What lies ahead is not peaceful.
目の前に広がるのは
平穏な未来ではない。
覚悟はできています。
I'm prepared for it.
Good.
うむ。
お前なら　やってくれるじゃろ。
I know you can do it.
そんなとこで　どうしたってばね？
What are you doing there?
三代目様からのお呼び出しは→
What did Lord Third want with you?
何だったの？
ああ…。
Well...
Did you get scolded?
何か　お小言をもらったのね。
So what?
Don't worry about it, ya know!
平気　平気！　そんなの→
気にすることないってばね！
いや　そうじゃなくて。
Well, it wasn't that...
Then what?
じゃあ　何だってばね？
Well...
あの…　四代目の火影をやれと。
He wants me to be
the Fourth Hokage.
そうだってばね。
Oh really?
Don't mind the Hokage—
火影なんか　気にすることない…。
What?! What did you just say?
今　何て言ったってばね！？
I've been named the Fourth Hokage.
四代目火影を仰せつかった。
Congratulations, ya know!
おめでとうだってばね！
Hey, hey...
おいおい！
お役目　ご苦労さまです！
Thank you very much for
all your hard work.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
ヒルゼンの思惑どおりの
流れになってしまった。
It's all going Hiruzen's way.
The Third Hokage intends to
use Minato as a puppet
（大蛇丸）三代目の本心は
ミナトを傀儡とし→
師弟で木ノ葉を牛耳ることね。
and keep ruling the Hidden Leaf.
At this rate, the Hidden Leaf
has no future.
このままのやり方では
木ノ葉に未来はない。
まだ諦めることはありません。
Don't give up yet.
この研究が成功すれば→
If my research is successful,
木ノ葉隠れの権力を
掌握するなど　たやすいこと。
it will be easy to grasp
the power of the Hidden Leaf.
フン…。
To grasp power...
stronger measures must be prepared.
権力を握るためなら
多少　強引な手段を使う用意も。
When the time comes,
we won't be choosing measures.
時が来れば手段は選ばぬ。
しかし　今はまだ　その時ではない。
But, it's not time yet.
だいたい　あやつに人望があれば
もう少し　なんとか…。
Generally, if he's popular at all,
he should...
行くぞ　甲！　乙！　丙！
Let's go, Kinoe, Kinoto, Hinoe!
– Sir!
（３人）はっ！
I, HIRUZEN SARUTOBI, HEREBY ANNOUNCE
MY RESIGNATION AS HOKAGE, AND APPOINT
MINATO NAMIKAZE AS THE FOURTH HOKAGE.
SIGNED, THIRD HOKAGE HIRUZEN SARUTOBI
What's going on?!
な…　なんと！？
Hey, Kakashi!
（ガイ）お～い　カカシ！
「いかに死すべきか」！？
なんだ　これ…。
"How a Shinobi Should Die"?!
What is this?
Give it back.
返してくれ！
What's going on?
何ごとだ？
あっ　そうだった！
Oh yeah!
The Fourth Hokage
was just announced!
今　四代目火影が発表された！
Don't be shocked!
びっくりすんなよ？
Minato Sensei will be
the Fourth Hokage!
四代目火影は　ミナト先生だ！
RIN NOHARA
Rin...
リン…。
It seems like Minato Sensei
is going to be Hokage!
ミナト先生が火影になるそうだよ。
Minato Sensei will be
the Professor's successor
先生なら
プロフェッサーの後継者となり→
and change the Hidden Leaf...
and the shinobi world.
木ノ葉隠れの里を…。
忍の世界を変えてくれる。
もう　お前たちのような
犠牲を出すことは…。
There won't be any more sacrifices
like you guys...
I'm counting on you...
Fourth Hokage.
頼むぞ　四代目。
一命にかえても。
I shall dedicate my life to it.
Kakashi. You shouldn't use
that jutsu anymore.
((カカシ　さっきのあの術は
もう使わないほうがいい。
From what I could see,
見たところ　一点集中型の突き。
your focused concentrated attack
undoubtedly has power and speed...
確かに破壊力とスピードはあるけど→
But it makes you move too fast
自分自身の移動スピードが速すぎて→
to be able to ascertain
your opponent's counterattack.
相手のカウンターを
見切ることができない→
It's still an imperfect jutsu.
(不完全な術だからね))
Those were Minato Sensei's words
back then...
《あのとき　ミナト先生は
ああおっしゃったが…》
Obito...
《オビト…》
I'm giving you... my Sharingan.
((オビト：この　俺の写輪眼を
やるからよ。
Whatever the village may say...
you are... a great jonin.
里のヤツらが何て言おうと
お前は立派な上忍だ。
That's how I really feel...
So please accept it.
それが　俺の気持だ。
(受け取ってくれ))
You gave me this Sharingan
in my left eye...
《お前にもらった
この左目の写輪眼。
When Chidori and Sharingan became one,
it became a complete jutsu.
千鳥と写輪眼が一つになったとき
この術は完全になった。
But... that jutsu took Rin's life.
しかし　その術でリンの命を…》
Chidori!
千鳥！
So this is where you've been!
こんなところにいたのか。
You have a mission.
You've been summoned immediately.
任務だから　すぐ出頭しろって。
Enter.
どうぞ。
任務ですか？
There's a mission?
Yes, I want you to retrieve the documents
relating to the peace treaty.
ああ。　平和条約に関する書類を
受け取ってきてもらいたい。
Yes.
はい。
There are still some shinobi
who desire war.
忍の中には
まだ戦乱の世を望む勢力もいる。
And there are rumors that they are trying
to steal the documents to create discord.
その者たちが書類を奪い→
仲違いさせようとしている
という情報がある。
Please do your best on this mission.
心して任務にかかってくれ。
Yes, sir.
はい。
I'll wrap this up!
《一気に　かたをつける！　千鳥》
Chidori!
Kakashi...
((リン：カカシ…。
カカシ　カカシ。
Kakashi...
(カカシ！))
Kakashi!
Die!
死ね！
Severe Leaf Hurricanes!
（ガイ）木ノ葉　剛力旋風！
クッ！　新手か？
Another one?
お前らしくもない！
何をぼやっとしている！
This isn't like you!
Why are you spaced out?
S-Sorry...
す　すまん…。
カカシ？
Kakashi?
Get a hold of yourself!
しっかりしろ！
I see...
そうか…。
はい。
Yes...
I've never seen Kakashi like that.
あんなカカシは
見たことがありません。
I'm glad I secretly sent you.
密かに同行してもらって
よかったよ。
To help him at a time like this...
That's what an eternal rival is for!
こんなときこそ
永遠のライバルとしては→
何かしてやらないと！
とは思うのですが！
That's what I believe, but...
You've already done a lot.
もう十分やってくれた。
あとは任せてもらえるかな。
Will you leave the rest to me?
HIDDEN LEAF HOSPITAL
ん？
Minato Sensei! I mean... Lord Fourth...
ミナト先生！
いや　四代目！
今までどおりの呼び名でいいよ。
Address me as you always have.
Some in the village think I'm not qualified
for the position and oppose me.
だいたい
俺がふさわしい人材なのか→
里の中でも
反対の立場の者もいるしね。
今日　ここに来たのは→
I came here today...
キミに　火影直属の
暗部への配属を命じるためだ。
to assign you to the ANBU
under my direct control.
Why me?
なぜ俺なんかを…。
右腕となって働いてもらいたい。
I want you to be my right-hand man...
AN
HOW A SHINOBI SHOULD DIE
EQUIPMENT DEPT.
Here's a set of gear for you.
あなたの装備一式です。
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
I already know
wakatten da yo
it doesn't belong to anyone else
hoka no dare demo nakute
I'll follow all the rainbows in the sky
kono sora ippai no niji wo kakete miseru yo
now matter how much time passes I can never reach it
itsumade tattemo todokanai yo
I keep repeating the same thing every day
ato nankai mo kurikaesu nichijou
I'm chasing a future I once dreamed of
oikaketeru no wa itsuka jibun de egaita mirai
and I was blaming it all on someone else
mata dareka no sei ni shiteta
I already know
wakatten da yo
that I can't go on like this
kono mama ja dame na koto
can I even believe in the "future self" I saw with my own eyes anymore?
kono me de midashita ashita no jibun wa mou shinjite ii n desu ka
I already know
wakatten da yo
that I have to go
ikanakucha ikenai koto
beyond the rainbow there's another future waiting for me
niji no mukou de matteru mou hitotsu no mirai he
I want you to leave your current mission
and take on a special mission.
＜旬の野菜が大好きな豆助＞
Was there an issue?
It's nothing like that.
This is confidential, but...
Kushina's pregnant!
豆助
Congratulations!
Thank you. That's why...
きょうのお野菜は
今が旬のあれよ？
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Minato's Death."
＜　その野菜とは？＞
... I want you to be Kushina's bodyguard.
＜　それは…＞